Guide to the Records of the Office of the Registrar RG.12.4
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the Registrar
1832-1916
New York University Archives
New York University. Office of the Registrar
Tompkins, Leslie J. (Leslie Jay), 1867-1952
Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
Ladue, Pomeroy
RG.12.4
4.4 Linear Feet in 18 custom boxes
The Office of the Registrar is responsible for the integrity of academic policies, the student information system and student records from application to degree conferral. The office works to protect and preserve the academic records of New York University's students and to provide a framework for students to navigate the academic process. The Records of the Office of the Registrar consist of 18 handwritten ledgers dating between 1832 and 1916. The majority of the ledgers track applications for admission, student matriculation, class rolls, grades, and citations for meritorious conduct.
Scope and Contents
The Records of the Office of the Registrar comprise handwritten ledgers dating between 1832 and 1916. The majority of the ledgers track applications for admission, student matriculation, class rolls, grades, and citations for meritorious conduct. A scrapbook compiled by the college's first registrar, Leslie J. Tompkins, documents the construction of and repairs to several buildings on the Heights Campus; endowments, scholarships, and prizes granted to students; commencement and lecture programs; and annual reports from the Treasurer's and the Registrar's offices. One volume lists officers and platoons, possibly in an early campus security organization; roll calls and lists of officers sent on patrol; and entries documenting arrests. One volume consists of a letterbook, containing letters written by J. J. Stevenson as registrar and Pomeroy Ladue as secretary regarding admission, coursework, and commencement in the graduate school in the 1890s.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials. The accession numbers associated with this collection are 90.020 and 2019.113.
Ledgers (account books); Universities and Colleges -- Admission.
- Matriculation Book, 1832-1843 (Box 1)
- Matriculation Books, 1853-1909 (Box 2)
- Class Merit Book, 1835-1888 (Box 3)
- Records of Grades, Department of Arts and Science, 1884-1894 (Box 15)
- Record Book, University College, 1886-1894 (Box 4)
- Record Book, University College, 1895-1897 (Box 5)
- Records of Grades, University College, 1890-1902 (Box 6)
- Records of Grades, School of Applied Science, Volume I, 1900-1909 (Box 7)
- Records of Grades, University College, 1900-1909 (Box 8)
- Records of Grades, School of Applied Science, Volume II, 1907-1909 (Box 9)
- Records of Actions on Applications for Admission, 1896-1900 (Box 12)
- Registrar's File, 1896-1904 (Box 11)
- Letterbook of Registrar of the Graduate School, 1890-1897 (Box 13)
- Attendance books, 1881-1891 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
- List of Students with Addresses and Activities, 1895-1903 (Box 16)
- Columbian Exposition Register of signatures of members of the University of the City of New York, 1893 (Box 17)
- Student rolls from University College and School of Applied Science, 1905-1916 (Box 14, Folder 3-6)
- New York University Ledger, 1870-1871 (Box 18)
- Faculty of Applied Science Students on Probation, 1908-1909 (Box 10)